const questions = [
  {
    "question": "An airborne weather radar unit transmits a 5\u00b0 beam from a parabolic dish aerial reflector assembly. If the wavelength is 4 cm, the diameter of the dish is:",
    "options": [
      "20 cm",
      "87.5 cm",
      "87.5 ins",
      "56.0 cm"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "On a colour radar, a bright red echo indicates:",
    "options": [
      "An area of strong wind shear",
      "An area of extreme turbulence",
      "Strong rising air currents",
      "Heavy concentrations of liquid/solid water"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "An airborne weather radar, with a beam width of 4\u00b0 in azimuth, is used in mapping mode. At what maximum range would it be able to detect a 1 NM wide opening in a facing sea cliff?",
    "options": [
      "4 NM",
      "60 NM",
      "45 NM",
      "15 NM"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flying at 25,000 ft is equipped with AWR. The beam width is 5\u00b0 with the radar tilted up at 3.5\u00b0. The radar is showing the top of a cloud return at 105 nm. The approximate height of the cloud is:",
    "options": [
      "14,300 ft",
      "25,600 ft",
      "30,300 ft",
      "35,600 ft"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The AWR can be used on the ground provided: The AWR can be used on the ground provided: i. The aircraft is clear of personnel, buildings and vehicles ii. The conical beam is selected iii. Maximum uplift is selected iv. The AWR must never be operated on the ground ",
    "options": [
      "The aircraft is clear of personnel, buildings and vehicles",
      "All correct except iv",
      "Maximum uplift is selected",
      "i only"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "On a colour radar, the greatest turbulence is likely in an area where the targets:",
    "options": [
      "Coloured red",
      "Coloured magenta",
      "Show a clearly defined hole",
      "Show a rapid gradient of change from magenta to yellow"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Before commencing a flight the weather radar should:",
    "options": [
      "Be switched to stand-by but not used until airborne",
      "Not be switched on until clear of buildings",
      "Be switched to a range function after push back to make sure it is functioning",
      "Be kept at stand-by until line up with the runway"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Weather radar is used by the pilot to assist in the:",
    "options": [
      "Detection and avoidance of all turbulence",
      "Detection and avoidance of potentially turbulent cloud cells",
      "Detection and determination of a route through active cloud formations",
      "Detection of other aircraft through clouds"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "AWR in the contour mode is used for:",
    "options": [
      "Identifying rain bearing clouds",
      "Long range mapping",
      "Short range mapping",
      "Identifying areas of maximum turbulence within a cloud"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The iso-echo feature of an airborne weather radar can be used to detect:",
    "options": [
      "Wake turbulence",
      "CAT",
      "Turbulence in clouds",
      "Areas of possible turbulence in clouds"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following wavelengths would give the best penetration of weather?",
    "options": [
      "25 cm",
      "50 cm",
      "10 cm",
      "3 cm"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "The DME ground transponder has a PRF of:",
    "options": [
      "2700 pulses per second",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "How many aircraft will DME accommodate before reaching saturation:",
    "options": [
      "100",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The time taken for the transmission of an interrogation pulse by a Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) to travel to the ground transponder and return to the airborne receiver was 2000 micro-second. The slant range from the ground transponder was:",
    "options": [
      "165 NM",
      "186 NM",
      "296 NM",
      "330 NM"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "If a VOR station and a DME station, having different locations, are selected to provide a fix:",
    "options": [
      "Two difference IDs will have to be checked",
      "Two positions, being ambiguous, will be presented",
      "Two sets, with separate frequency control, are required in the aircraft",
      "All 3 answers above are correct"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Groundspeed measurement using DME equipment is most accurate flying:",
    "options": [
      "From the station at long range",
      "Over the station",
      "Towards the station at short range",
      "Past the station at short range"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Where a DME uses mechanical counters for displaying the range, continuous rotation of the counters means:",
    "options": [
      "The DME is in a search mode",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The DME in an aircraft, cruising at FL 210, fails to achieve lock on a DME at MSL at a range of 210 nm. The reason for this is:",
    "options": [
      "The aircraft is beyond line of sight range",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum distance apart a VOR and TACAN can be located and have the same identification?",
    "options": [
      "2000 m",
      "60 m",
      "600 m",
      "6 m"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "When identifying a co-located VOR/DME the following signals are heard in the Morse code every 30 seconds?",
    "options": [
      "4 identifications in the same tone",
      "4 identifications with the DME at a higher tone",
      "4 identifications with the DME at a lower tone",
      "No DME identification..."
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "A VOR and DME are frequency paired. The DME identification ends with Z. This denotes that:",
    "options": [
      "The two beacons are co-located",
      "The beacons are supporting the same site but are not co-located",
      "The beacons are greater than 2000 m apart",
      "The beacons are at the same location but are more than 1000 m apart"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "In a certain VORTAC installation the VOR is coding STN and the DME is coding STZ. This means that the distance between the two beacons is in excess of:",
    "options": [
      "600 m",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft at FL 360 is 10 nm plan range from a DME. The DME reading in the aircraft will be:",
    "options": [
      "11.7 nm",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft DME receiver is able to accept replies to its own transmission and reject replies to other aircraft interrogations because:",
    "options": [
      "Transmission frequencies are 63 MHz different for each aircraft",
      "Pulse pairs are amplitude modulated...",
      "Aircraft interrogation signals and...",
      "Pulse pairs are discrete to a particular aircraft"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "A DME transmitter is operating in the search-for-lock phase. Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "options": [
      "The PRF increases and the range counters count down from the maximum",
      "The PRF increases and the range counters count up from 300 to maximum",
      "The PRF increases and the power is increased",
      "The PRF increases, the range counters count down from maximum..."
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Height error has the greatest effect on accuracy when an aeroplane is:",
    "options": [
      "Over the base line extensions at low altitude",
      "At the base line bisector at low altitudes",
      "At the base line bisector at high altitude",
      "Over the base line extension at high altitude"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "DME is a radar type of facility and its maximum range is limited by:",
    "options": [
      "The pulse repetition interval",
      "The height of the aeroplane",
      "The transmitter power",
      "The receiver sensitivity"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "In DME, interrogation and responses are separated by 63 MHz in order to:",
    "options": [
      "Avoid station saturation",
      "Differentiate between precision and ordinary DME",
      "Facilitate channel selection",
      "Prevent self-triggering"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "A DME which is listed as operating on an 'X' channel is one which:",
    "options": [
      "Is paired exclusively with an ILS frequency",
      "Is paired exclusively with a TACAN frequency",
      "Responds on a frequency 63 MHz higher than the interrogation frequency",
      "Responds on a frequency 63 MHz lower than the interrogation frequency"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The nominal maximum coverage of a DME station is:",
    "options": [
      "150 nm at 20,000 ft",
      "175 nm at 25,000 ft",
      "190 nm at 25,000 ft",
      "200 nm at 30,000 ft"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the DME tell different aircraft apart:",
    "options": [
      "By using a jittered PRF",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correct": 0
  }
];
